

 $\overline{\phantom{a}}$ 

singalanil1995@gmail.com

[] 9970469391

Q

Balaji Boys Hostel Narhe, Pune Maharashtra, India

in

linkedin.com/in/anil-singal-556175186

0

github.com/AnilSingal99

## **SKILLS**

Python

Pandas

Numpy

R

Data Analysis

Data Visualization

Machine Learning

Power BI

Tableau

SOL

Excel

MS-Office

Word

Power-Point

## **LANGUAGES**

#### English

Full Professional Proficiency

#### HInd

Full Professional Proficiency

#### Marath

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

### **INTERESTS**

Listening Music

Playing Cricket

Swimming

# **Anil Singal**

Data Analyst

Experienced Data Analyst with a demonstrated history of working in the Analytics industry. Skilled in Base Python, R programming, SQL, and Excel with Data Visualization tool Tableau, Power BI. Strong Computer Science Professional with an MCA focused on Programming from (SIMCA) Pune.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Data Analyst**

## Improx Data & Cloud Consulting Pvt Ltd

08/2019 - 08/2020

Pune Maharashtra

Tasks

- Data visualization and data handling by using many function data visualization with graphs, pie charts, bar charts, and column charts.
- Data extract from multiple sources that can be primary or secondary. After that, they organize
  the data in a proper format that can be easily understood.
- Data cleaning, filtering, and reporting using various functions like Pivot Tables, V-lookup, H-lookup, count if, index, and match in excel.
- Creating report and Dashboard in Power BI, Tableau and Excel.
- Working on More Spreadsheet.
- Designing database tables and structures.
- Creating views, functions and stored procedures.
- Writing optimized SQL queries for integration with other applications.
- Data Preprocessing, Data Cleaning, Data Visualization, Data Analysis using python libraries.

# **Data Science & Business Analytics Intern**The Sparks Foundations

10/2020 - 11/2020

Tasks

- I have worked on supervised machine learning algorithms, linear regression with python scikitlearn
- Prediction using Unsupervised Machine learning, To Explore Unsupervised Machine Learning K-Means Clustering with Python Scikit-Learn.
- I have worked on Pandas, NumPy, Seaborn and Matplotlib libraries.

#### CERTIFICATES

Certified Data Scientist From Jigsaw Academy Bangalore (2019)

Python for Data Analysis & Data Visualization Certified By Udemy (2020)

Power BI Desktop Certified By Coursera (2020)

#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

Titanic Data Analysis & Visualization. (09/2020 - 10/2020)

- Dijective:-To analyzed data by Age, P-class, Survived, Gender.
- Libraries:- Python, Pandas, Numpy, Seaborn, Matplotlib.
- □ **Tool:-** Anaconda, Jupyter Notebook.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master Of Computer Application (MCA)
Sinhgad Institute Of Management & Computer Application Pune
07/2016 - 05/2019

Bachelor Of Computer Science (BCS)
Dr. BAMU Aurangabad

07/2013 - 04/2016